Hugh A. Moran Papers WLU.Coll.0005
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Hugh A. Moran Papers
Inclusive 1865-1879
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Moran, Hugh A. (Hugh Anderson)
Boyd, Alston
Johnston, William Preston
Moran, Nathan M.
Desha, Lucius, Jr.
WLU.Coll.0005
180 Item
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Hugh Anderson Moran, 1947.
Scope and Contents
Mainly correspondence, including letters between Hugh A. Moran and his family while he was a student at Washington College; letters from fellow students; college programs; class notebook. Correspondents include Alston Boyd, Lucius Desha, Jr., William Preston Johnston, Mildred Lee, Nathan M. Moran and Mrs. Nathan M. Moran.
Greek letter societies; College Students; Note-taking; Correspondence; Printed ephemera; Literature; Societies; Lee, Robert E., General (Robert Edward); Lee, George Washington; Barclay family; Lee family; Louisville and Nashville Railroad; Washington College (Lexington, Va.)
- Correspondence, 1845-1947; 1; 3 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists primarily of the correspondence of Alfred I. duPont, but it also includes some of the correspondence of his wives Alicia Bradford Maddox duPont and Jessie Ball duPont. Consequently, the series has been arranged alphabetically by these three individuals.Alfred's business affairs are documented in his correspondence with merchants and manufacturers, as well as in his correspondence with duPont managers such as Edward Ball. Family and personal affairs are reflected in Alfred's correspondence with family members such as brother Maurice duPont and sister Marguerite duPont Lee. Alfred's main personal correspondents are his daughter Madeleine Hiebler in Munich, Germany, and his wife Jessie.The series also documents aspects of Alfred I. duPont's charitable giving. Recipients of contributions represented in this series include the American Committee for Devastated France, the welfare home of Smyrna, Delaware, and Reverend H.M. Bartlett of Christ Church in Wilmington.Correspondence of or relating to Alicia Bradford Maddox duPont consist primarily of exchanges with her mother Eleuthera duPont Bradford. In addition, there are several files of condolence letters to Alfred following Alicia's death in 1920. Letters of sympathy after Alfred's death in 1935 constitute the correspondence of Jessie Ball duPont.
  - Alfred I. Du Pont
    - Correspondence with daughter Madeleine Hiebler 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Letter from William Jervey to E.G. Bradford 1837 January 27, 1837-01-27 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Christmas Card, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with family members including siblings Maurice duPont and Marguerite Lee, and son Alfred Victor; topics include old age pension 1927-1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alicia Bradford Maddox Du Pont
    - Eleuthera Paulina Du Pont Bradford, 1885-1904 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Eleuthera Bradford, 1890, 1904-1905, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Mainly correspondence with Eleuthera Bradford, 1896-1904, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Eleuthera Bradford, 1901-1905, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Financial and Business Records
- Photographs, 1870-1927